（六千五百万年前的白垩纪）
巨齿鲨2：深渊
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
（现今）
? Pressure pushing down on me ?
? Pressing down on you No man ask for ?
? Under pressure That burns a building down ?
? Splits a family in two ?
? Puts people on streets ?
? It's the terror of knowing ?
? What this world is about ?
? Watching some good friends ?
? Screaming, "Let me out"?
? Pray tomorrow Gets me higher ?
? Pressure on people People on streets ?
（菲律宾海）
（有毒废弃物）
这东西超毒的
It's highly toxic.
快点 小子 继续搬运 不要停
Come on, lads, keep it moving. Keep it moving.
（蓝猫号）
快点 快点
Go, go, go!
搬这个有双倍酬劳吗
Is this double pay or what?
毕竟是有毒废弃物
There is toxic waste.
你杵在那里干嘛 都到船边了
What are you doing sitting there, mate?  You're almost there.
快点把这些垃圾丢下船
I want this filth off my ship as fast as possible.
你在干嘛
What you doing, then?
坏坏
Naughty.
来人啊 来人啊
Help! Help!
坏坏
Naughty.
闭上你的鸟嘴
Keep your little beak shut. Not very nice.
-真不乖 -不然丢你下海
Otherwise, you'll go for a swim.
来人啊 来人啊
- Help! Help!
快来救我 快来救我
Help me! Help me!
干得好
Well done.
是总部派我来的
I'm here from the home office.
放屁
Bullshit.
来这里检查安全协定
Here checking on, uh, security protocols...
顺便拍几张照片 笑一个
...and, um, taking a few pictures, so smile.
你们在里面干嘛
What are you doing in here?
-真不乖 -这是怎么回事
-  Not very nice. - What's going on?
就是他
That's him!
我要抓住你
I'll get you!
喂 快去帮忙
Hey, hey! Get at this!
-上去 -抓住他
-  Get up. -  Get Him down!
你们两个往左边 拦截他
You two, go left! Cut him off!
一定要把他抓到 死的也行
I want him caught, dead or dead.
别走那里 绕过去 绕过去
Not there! Go around! Go around!
好了 兄弟 游戏结束了
There you go, mate. End of the line.
好
Okay.
你们都被捕了
You're all under arrest.
罪名是非法倾倒放射性毒物
For the illegal dumping of radioactive materials.
对 你 你 你 你和你
Yeah, you, you, you, you and you.
什么 我和他还有他 跟他
What, me and... and him, and him? And him?
-杀了他 -等等 等等
- Kill him. -  Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
我知道你们想看逮捕令
I know. You want to see the warrant.
就在我口袋里
It's right in my pocket.
我们法庭上见 好吗
I'll see you in court, yeah?
这里偏离航运线 离海岸还有两百浬
We're out of shipping lanes, and you're 200 miles from shore.
祝你游个痛快
So enjoy your swim.
看到他了 就在左舷边
I've got him. Just off the port side.
他就像环保版007 我喜欢
He's like a green James Bond. I like it.
不 我的帽子
Oh, no, my hat!
嗨 蠢蛋们
Hello, suckers.
看来他交了很多新朋友
Looks like he's been making friends.
不管走到哪 他都一样受欢迎
Wherever he goes, people just love him.
天知道为什么
God knows why.
你能搞定吗
Do you got this?
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
或许这不是最好的主意
Maybe this wasn't the best idea.
Maybe this isn't the best idea.
这一定会很棒
This is gonna be awesome.
解释一下很棒的定义
Define "awesome."
我正要示范
I'm about to.
开启舱门
Opening hatch.
下次给这东西多充点气
Next time, put a little more air in this thing.
我好像用吸管在呼吸
It's like breathing through a straw.
但的确有用 不是吗
Worked, didn't it?
你还好吗
You okay?
若你热爱自己职业 就永远不觉得辛苦
If you love your job, you'll never work a day in your life.
（万溟鲸灵研究所 海南高科技产业园）
好 把15号测试品带进来
Okay, bring in Test 15.
开启机甲动力
Initiating suit power-up.
净空
Clear.
很有潜力
Promising.
外骨骼机甲的表现超出我们预期 九溟
The exo suit is performing way beyond what we expected, Jiuming.
动力增加了21%
21% increase in power.
还不错吧
Not bad, huh?
非常酷
So cool.
我等不及要在海沟中使用
I can't wait to use these in the trench.
你好
Hi.
有什么指示
What's up favourite niece?
今晚你能别迟到吗 舅
I'm supposed to tell you not to be late for the party tonight.
怎么可能 你交代的事
Of course.
-或许加到25 -好
-  Maybe 25. Hmm? - Okay.
我是认真的 别迟到
I mean it, don't be late!
你人生活到这一步 还不会打领带也太扯了
I cannot believe you got this far in life without knowing how to tie a tie.
首先 不要夸大我的人生进程
First, let's not overstate how far I've gotten in life.
其次 干我这行不需要穿西装
Second, never involved wearing a monkey suit.
-完美 你看起来超帅 -谢谢
- Perfect. You look great. - Thanks.
或许你能开始习惯社交
Ah. Maybe this is the start of something.
别想太多
Don't count on it.
你好
Hi.
那个人你眼熟吗
That guy look familiar to you?
不熟
No.
-我不喜欢他 -你谁都不喜欢
-  I don't like him. - You don't like anyone.
我就喜欢你
I like you.
因为我总是替你擦屁股
That's 'cause I save your life all the time...
给你买酒喝 还在酒吧斗殴时支援你
I buy you beers and I back you up in bar fights.
因为你是很特别的人
It's 'cause you're a special guy.
你们都很特别
You're both special.
-祝我好运 -祝你好运
- Wish me luck. -  Good luck.
感谢捐款
Thanks for the money.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎来到本海洋研究所的十周年庆
welcome to the 10th anniversary of the Oceanic Institute.
我是希拉蕊德斯科
I'm Hilary Driscoll.
感谢各位今晚的光临 并与我
Thank you for coming tonight, and for joining me
一起赞助这项惊人的研究
in funding this incredible work.
停 别搓来蹭去的
Stop. Don't fidget.
我为何必须出席这活动
Why exactly do I have to be up here anyway?
因为你很合群
'Cause you're a team player.
好极了
Great.
请掌声热烈欢迎本研究所的所长
Please give a warm welcome to the director of the Institute...
张九溟
...Zhang Jiuming.
谢谢你 希拉蕊
Thank you, Hilary.
明朝的大文人宋濂说…
As the great poet Song Lian said...
「上凌霄汉 下烛九溟」
"Man is limited only by his imagination."
我爸给我取名叫九溟
My father named me Jiuming,
意思是海洋或者深渊
which means ocean or abyss.
我爸我姐毕生都在研究海洋
My father and my sister spent their lives studying the ocean.
可惜年轻的时候我不懂事
It wasn't until they were both gone that I began to wonder
直到他们都走了
what my purpose was.
我才开始琢磨
But through Suyin's daughter Meiying,
自己为什么活着
I saw that there was a future.
我把父亲的研究所 和我的万溟鲸灵公司合并
I merged my father's research institute with my company
就是为了要发扬 中国人这种探索未知世界的精神
to carry forward the spirit of exploring the unknown in their honor.
值此十周年之际
To mark this tenth anniversary,
我想向大家介绍一位真正的大美女
I want to introduce you all to someone very special.
它叫海琪
Her name is Haiqi.
我们发现它的时候 它受了伤
She is the world's only megalodon in captivity.
于是我们把它带回来治疗扶养
We found her injured as a pup.
海琪变得很热情 它邀请我们
Thanks to Haiqi, we've learned a tremendous amount about the megalodons
去它家作客
as well as the trench where they live.
（潜艇一号）
多亏了我们支持者的慷慨捐助
Thanks to the generous donations from our supporters,
我们得以开发出穿越温跃层的技术
we have been able to create the technology to pass through the thermocline,
这层冰冷的海水 将海琪的世界与我们世界隔开
a thermal layer of freezing cold water that separates Haiqi's world from ours
并潜入海平面以下六千米的海沟
and into a trench 6,000 meters below sea level.
多亏了各位 让我们能比以往走得更远
Thanks to you, we have the ability to go further than ever before.
保护海洋 对中国 对人类 都很重要
Love the ocean and protect the ocean.
谢谢
Thank you
也谢谢你 张九溟
And thank you. Zhang Jiuming.
所以感谢大家
So, thank you all
和我们一起保护这神奇的生态系统
for being part of protecting this incredible ecosystem.
感谢光临
Thank you for coming.
你认为那里有 更多的海底生物被发现
Do you think there are more creatures to be discovered down there?
必须的须啊
There has to be.
有谁想跟曾与巨齿鲨搏斗
Who wants to get a selfie with the man
并成功存活的男人合影自拍
who fought a megalodon and lived to tell the tale?
女士们先生们 请欢迎乔纳斯泰勒
We give you, ladies and gentlemen, Jonas Taylor.
他在那里 他在那里
There he is! There he is.
我知道这是你的主意
I know this was your idea.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
微笑 并假装你乐在其中
Smile and pretend you love it.
来啊 给他一个抱抱和搔搔痒
Go on, give him a hug. Give him a tickle.
他最爱拥抱群众了
Oh, he loves people.
我想跟你一起去玛纳一号
I wanna go to Mana One with you.
我想潜入海沟
I want to dive the trench.
不行
No.
抱歉 玫盈
Sorry, Meiying.
为什么不行
Why not?
我妈在我这年纪时就常潜水
Mom was diving all the time at my age.
但不是潜两万五千呎
Not to 25,000 feet.
意思是太危险
Saying it's too dangerous?
对你来说太危险
Too dangerous for you.
但实际上并不危险
But not dangerous.
在心理学上 这叫“认知失调”
In psychology, they call that "cognitive dissonance."
在现实世界中 这叫“父母心”
In the real world, they call it "parenting."
你需要开始认真地 把我当成科学家看待
You need to start taking me seriously as a scientist.
你才14岁
You're 14.
没错
Exactly.
我熟知玛纳一号上的每个系统 每个潜水协议
I know every system on Mana One, every dive protocol
以及在那里看到的每种动物
and every animal we've seen down there.
听着 你可以登上玛纳一号
Hey, look. You can come to Mana One.
从旁观测我们潜水
To observe the dive.
仅此而已
And that's it.
九溟跑去和巨齿鲨共游了
Jiuming is swimming with the meg.
舅舅
Uncle.
海琪的生命指数飙高
Haiqi's vitals are elevated.
小心点 它知道你也在水中
Be careful, she's definitely aware of you.
九溟 你为何要与巨齿鲨共游
Why are you swimming with the meg, Jiuming?
我正在进行一项实验
I'm conducting an experiment.
而实验叫“我好吃吗 ”
Is the experiment "Do I taste good?"
舅 你疯啦
Uncle, are you crazy?
没事的
It's okay.
我从海琪小时候就开始训练它了
I've been training Haiqi since she was a pup.
你无法驯服巨齿鲨 九溟
A meg is not trainable, Jiuming.
若你想在外甥女面前被吃掉 请便吧
But if you wanna be eaten in front of your niece, go ahead.
我赌五十元结果会是悲剧
Fifty bucks says this is gonna end badly.
我赌了
I'll take that action.
我押鲨鱼队赢
I am all in for team shark.
什么 不能押鲨鱼赢 那算造孽
What? You can't bet on a shark, man. That's bad karma.
拜托各位 专心工作 这样不好
Come on, guys, focus. That's not cool.
九溟 良心建议这主意真的糟透了
Jiuming... I'd like to respectfully suggest that this is truly a terrible idea.
巨齿鲨和人类根本不该相交
Megs and humanity were never meant to mix.
我与海琪心有灵犀
Haiqi and I have a special bond.
你们瞧
Watch this.
按一次响片代表过来 按两次响片代表离开
One click to come. Two clicks to go.
妈啊 我觉得它在看我们
Whoa. I think she's looking at us.
看到了吗
You see?
它绕回来了 心率飙高
She's coming around. Heart rate is up.
快速迫近
Moving in fast.
（九溟 海琪）
四百米
Four hundred meters.
悠悠的 悠悠的
Slowly, slowly.
-九溟 它完全没回应 -听话 海琪
Jiuming, she's not responding. Come on, Haiqi.
两百米
Two hundred meters.
一百米
One hundred meters.
九溟 快闪
Jiuming, move.
来不及了 它速度太快了
It's too late. She's coming in too fast.
五十米
Fifty meters.
快拉安全索
Pull the cord.
二十米
Twenty meters.
-九溟 快离开 -舅 不要
Jiuming, get out of there! Uncle, no!
它咬到他了吗
Did it get him?
我不知道 我不敢看
I don't know. I couldn't watch.
他不见了
I don't see him.
我就说这是个馊主意
I knew this was a bad idea.
刺激吗 亲
Total success.
舅舅 你脑袋进水啦
Uncle! Are you crazy?
我这不没事吗
It's all right, I'm good.
那很刺激 对吧
That was exciting, huh?
我不知道它是怎么了
I can't figure out what's wrong with her.
它这整周的行为都很异常
She's been acting strangely all week.
就算你把响片按烂也没用
You can clickety-click all you want.
症结是 它是一只巨齿鲨
The problem is that it's a meg.
而你是点心
And you're a snack.
对
Yeah.
重点是 你把玫盈吓坏了
For the record, you scared the hell out of Meiying.
你也好意思训我 你跑去那艘船上干嘛
You're one to talk. What were you doing on that ship?
算了 别告诉我 我不想知道
Actually, don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
本研究所的宗旨就是保护海洋 对吧
Well, the Institute's mandate is to protect the oceans, right?
我们不能参与任何非法活动
We can't be a part of any illegal activity.
我最厌恶违法乱纪
Oh, I abhor lawlessness.
是喔 那好
Oh, good.
特别是非法倾倒放射性废弃物
Especially the illegal dumping of radioactive waste.
随着每次行动 风险都会增加
You're taking bigger and bigger risks each time you go out.
在这点上我们还蛮有共识的
Well, I guess we both know about that.
这完全不一样
It's not the same.
我的行为 风险是可预估的
With me, there's a calculation of risks.
我可不这么认为
Not that I see.
你想念你妈妈吗 大鱼
Do you miss your mom, big fish?
准备好前往玛纳一号了吗
Are you ready for Mana One?
我随时 主要看大小姐的胆气啊
Yes, whenever you're ready?
有了这玩意 我们在水底下可以安全去任何地方
These new suits will let us travel anywhere and at any depth underwater.
你瞧
Say.
搞什么
What?
没事 没事 没事
No worries, no worries.
我妈和姥爷经常提到你
Mom and Grandpa talked about you all the time.
都怎么骂我的啊
Nothing good I suppose.
你猜
Wanna guess?
看见这个疤了吗
See this scar?
我11岁的时候 趁着老师忙着做实验
When I was 11 my father was busy in the lab.
偷着约了个小伙伴 去乱石滩游野泳
So I snuck out to swim with my friends on the rocky shores...
缝了九针
and had to get nine stitches as a result of it.
回到家 老头狠狠地教训了我一顿
When I returned home my father taught me a real lesson.
我姥爷
Grandpa?
不然呢
Of course.
慈眉善目是对你这个外孙女
He was kind to you because you're his granddaughter,
对亲儿子 他狠着呢
but he was tough on me.
所以我长大以后 考大学 开公司 自己创业
So after college, I started a company.
只想跑得离他越远越好
I wanted to get away from him.
忽然有一天 很多年都不联系的他
I hadn't had any contact with your grandfather for many years.
让你妈给我送了这幅字
Then he asked your mum to bring me this calligraphy.
“四海游龙”
"Dragon travelling across the Four Seas."
我以为他是在嘲笑我
I thought it was a form of ridicule...
直到他们都走了 我才知道自己有多蠢
but I came to realize that he wanted me to find my own way.
这四个字也送给你
Like the dragon...
希望你自由地 主宰自己的命运
I hope you can find your own fate.
地勤人员 我们正接近玛纳一号
Ground crew, we're approaching Mana One.
嗨 芮格斯 欢迎你回来
Hey, Rigas. Good to have you back.
我想念你们
I missed you guys.
准备好要去潜水了吗
Are you ready to do some diving?
那还用说
You know it.
（玛纳一号海洋研究基地）
（海琪）
大家早安 让我们开始水下任务吧
Morning, everyone. Let's get this show underwater.
潜艇一号与潜艇二号 准备下潜两万五千呎
Dive 1 and Dive 2, descend to 25,000 feet.
本次任务要探索第19区
We're exploring Area 19.
收集岩石样本并记录任何新物种
Collecting rock samples and logging any new species.
20分钟后开始下潜
Diving in T-minus 20 minutes.
全员请仔细进行目视和扫描 就像常规那样
All eyes open for a straightforward sweep and scan. The usual.
是喔 水底没有常规可言
Yeah. There's no usual down there.
系统启动
System's up.
兰斯 你在中控台周围 挂满玩具是怎么回事
What's with all these toys you have hanging around your console, Lance?
那些不是玩具 它们是公仔
They're not toys, they're figurines.
它们绝对是玩具 兰斯
They are definitely toys, Lance.
谢了
Thank you.
准备好下水了吗 各位
Ready for the drop, guys?
所以你和莎尔会去参加动漫展吗
So, are you and Sal, like, Comic-Con guys or what?
完全正确 会
Uh, absolutely right. Yeah.
你会做角色扮演吗
Do you, um, dress up?
会
Uh, yeah.
别跟他聊这个 除非你想看一百万张照片
Don't get him started, unless you want to see a million photographs.
好啊 麻烦你
Oh, yes, please.
专心工作 各位
Stay focused, guys.
超越一万七千呎
Passing 17,000.
遥测数据正常
Telemetry's good.
又是海底美好的一天
It's a beautiful day in the neighborhood.
超越一万八千呎
Passing 18,000 feet.
所有系统运作正常
All systems nominal.
组员们 状况不错 请打开我们今天要勘测的座标
Looking good, team. Let's pull up the grids we're gonna map today.
第19区 我们什么时候才能看不同的东西
Area 19. When are we going to look at something different?
毕竟还有大约一百区需要探索
You know, there's like 100 more sectors to explore.
乔纳斯 你能确认氧气水平吗
Jonas, can you confirm O2 levels?
消耗量超过任务规格11%
Consumption is 11% over mission spec.
我猜芮格斯很紧张
Guess Rigas is nervous.
应该是因为你总用嘴巴呼吸
More like you're a mouth breather.
他真的是那样
He totally is.
-从这里都能感受到你呼出的气 -对
Can feel the breeze from over here. Yeah.
首先 那个叫作鼻中膈弯曲
Firstly, it's called a deviated septum.
再者 我清楚记得是在 从70呎巨齿鲨的口中
Second, I distinctly remember deviating it while saving your ungrateful ass
救下你时才弄弯的
from a 70-foot megalodon.
超越两万呎 接近温跃层
Passing 20,000 feet. Approaching the thermocline.
检查氧气管路和槽压
Checking O2 lines and tank pressure.
若真有外泄 读数会出现波动
Well, if there was a leak, there would be a fluctuation on the readings.
我这里完全没看到异常
I'm not seeing anything here.
检查辅助氧气储槽的压力
Check the pressure on the auxiliary O2 tanks. Okay, I'll check again.
问题不在那里
That's not the problem.
乔纳斯
Uh, Jonas?
玫盈
Meiying?
你搞什么鬼啊
What the hell are you doing?
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
我看得出来你很生气
I see that you're angry.
但我深信这个决定非常合理而且负责
But I believe that this is a reasonable and responsible decision.
停止下潜
Stop the dive.
全数暂停
Full stop.
但在你开始吼人前 我想说
But before you start yelling, can I just say...
我14岁时也做了很多蠢事
I did all kinds of stupid things when I was 14.
结果我还不是好好的
And look how I turned out.
返回海平面
We're surfacing.
但我不明白为何不行
But I don't see what the problem is.
这是你第26次进行海沟潜水 而且从无事故
This is your 26th trench dive without incident.
潜艇配有电流掠食者防御系统 和紧急潜水机甲
Subs have electric predator countermeasures, and emergency dive suits.
但没带你那份
Which you don't have.
其实嘛
Actually...
我在你们开行前会时准备了一套
I packed one while you were doing the pre-dive meeting.
知道吗
You know,
你或许应该先乖乖坐好 保持安静
now's maybe a good time to, uh, sit down and be quiet for a minute.
我可以自己系安全带
I can do a seatbelt by myself, you know.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
乔纳斯
Jonas.
这不归你管 九溟
It's not your call, Jiuming.
我们有访客了
We've got company.
各位 是一只巨齿鲨
Guys, it's a meg.
快速迫近
Approaching fast.
那不可能 它们无法通过温跃层
That's not possible. they can't go through the thermocline.
它不是来自温跃层 我是从岸边追踪它过来的
It's not come from the thermocline. I'm tracking it from the shore.
立刻全速下潜
Dive! Flank speed!
执行 重组电池阵列
Engaging. Rerouting battery array.
抓紧了
Hold on.
开启掠食者防御系统
Charging the predator countermeasures.
充好电前我们就会先阵亡
We'll be dead before they're online.
温跃层是我们唯一的出路
Thermocline's our only hope.
我看到海琪追踪器的读数
I'm reading Haiqi's tracker.
（潜艇一号 海琪 潜艇二号）
这不可能
Impossible.
不可能的刚变成可能了
Well, impossible just got possible.
距离温跃层五百米
Five hundred meters to the thermocline.
海琪正快速迫近
Haiqi's closing fast.
一百米
One hundred meters.
它就在我们正上方
She's right above us.
加油 加油啊
Come on, come on!
进入温跃层
Entering the thermocline.
潜艇一号 潜艇二号
Dive 1, Dive 2.
切换低频光 你们不会想吸引更多的巨齿鲨
Switch to low-frequency light. you don't want to attract any more megs.
它失去踪迹了 它无法跟着我们过来
I've lost her. She can't follow us through.
对吧
Can she?
暂停通讯
Going dark.
我从没用60节的速度穿越温跃层过
I've never crossed the thermocline at 60 knots.
小心 你可不想烧坏引擎
Careful. You don't want to burn out the engines.
别担心 我不会弄坏这豪华的玩具
Don't worry, I'm not gonna break the pretty toys.
成功
Yes.
（潜艇一号 潜艇二号 海琪）
它还在跟着我们
She's still on us.
三十秒后
Thirty seconds
防御系统上线
for the countermeasures.
回避
Evasive.
它一定是追踪了我们的热讯号
She must have followed our heat signature.
九溟 你的宠物鲨鱼是怎么下来的
How did your pet shark get down here, Jiuming?
它一定是逃脱了
She must have escaped.
那是怎么发生的
How did that happen?
掠食者防御系统启动
Predator countermeasures active.
迫近警报
Proximity alert.
多只巨齿鲨
Megs.
不可能
No way.
那是我见过最大的巨齿鲨
That's the biggest meg I've ever seen.
那是任何人见过最大的巨齿鲨
Biggest meg anyone's ever seen.
它一定是顶级掠食者
That's gotta be the apex predator.
不可思议 巨齿鲨是独居动物
Incredible. Megs are solitary.
它们仿佛是被召唤来此
It's like they're being called.
变更原定潜水计画 我们得去看看它们要干嘛
I'm changing the dive plan. We have to see what they're up to.
那玫盈怎么办
And what about Meiying?
我赞成去看看
Well, I vote we go.
没人在问你
I wasn't asking you.
目前的氧气储备量还在最大值
Oxygen reserves are at maximum.
掠食者防御系统也已布署
Predator countermeasures are deployed.
目前的我们绝对安全
Right now we are perfectly safe.
只是目前而已
Right now, yeah.
若我发现任何危险 就会立刻中止任务
If I see anything dangerous, I'm pulling the plug.
麦克 我们要更改任务内容
Mac, we're changing the mission profile.
前往227航向
Proceeding on heading 227.
他们已经偏离原任务了 至少得留在原航道
Now, they're already off mission. They need to stay on course.
乔纳斯 你们已远远驶出勘测过的区域
Jonas, you're going way outside the sector we have already mapped.
这是一次探索任务
This is an exploration mission.
让我们前去探索
Let's explore.
收到
Copy that.
睁大眼睛 注意后方动静
- Eyes open, watch your backs.
你是在说笑吧 麦克
Really, Mac?
我们要跟着巨型鲨前往未知区域
So, we're gonna follow some giant sharks to a unknown sector?
老天
Man...
这行为蠢毙了 记住我的警告
This some dumbass shit, mark my words.
进入第21区
Entering sector 21.
开始地理扫描
Commencing geographical scan.
这里好美
It's so beautiful.
你妈超爱这地方
Your mum loved this place more than anything.
我很高兴终于亲眼看到了
I'm glad I finally get to see it.
别太习惯
Don't get used to it.
你的余生都被禁足了
You're grounded for the rest of your life.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
海琪维持领先四百米
Haiqi 400 meters ahead and holding.
我们现在要去哪
Where are we going now?
进入未知领域
Into the unknown.
那正是我们此行的目的
That's what we came for.
海琪的追踪讯号在前方
I've got Haiqi's tracker ahead.
它好像在兜圈子
Looks like she's circling.
看上方
Look up.
它们在依循本能聚集
It's some instinctual gathering.
太惊人了
Incredible.
它们是来此交配的
They're here to mate.
所以海琪最近行为才会那么反常
This is why Haiqi has been acting strangely.
好极了 更多的巨齿鲨
Oh, great. More megs.
扫描仪检测到异常结构
The scanner's detecting an abnormal structure.
不可能
No way.
那是艘沉船吗
Is that a wreck?
那是某种海底基地
It's some kind of sea floor station.
建在这里是想要干嘛
What could they be doing down here?
芮格斯 进行全仪器扫瞄
Rigas, run all spectrums.
（红外线 热能扫描）
No, that's no wreck.
那不是沉船残骸 上面有热讯号
I'm getting heat signatures off it.
只是看不到里面有什么
Just can't see what's inside.
多个气闸舱 全区供电
Multiple airlocks, power generation.
能做到这样需要很大的资本
The resources needed is staggering.
谁会拥有这种技术
Who would even have that technology?
声纳显示我们上方有东西
Sonar says there's something above us.
看起来像一艘潜艇
It looks like a submarine.
我们去看看
Let's take a look.
炸药已就位 正在准备爆炸区域
Charges set. Priming zone for detonation.
快点 我们得炸平这海脊
Come on. We need to blow this ridge.
好啦 知道了
Yeah, okay, okay.
我们也不想在外面待太久
We don't wanna be down here any longer than needs be.
谁叫这是唯一可以开采这东西的地方
Yeah, well, this is the only place to mine this stuff.
慢慢来 别搞砸
Slow and steady.
蒙提斯 为什么你可以待在潜艇里
Hey, Montes. Why do you get to stay in the submarine?
这是当队长的特权
It's good to be the king.
检测有物体迫近
Incoming object detected.
放大四百倍
Zoom in 400%.
（四百倍聚焦）
玛纳一号组员出现在下方
Mana One crew is below us.
他们肯定已经发现基地了
There's no way they haven't seen the station.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我现在就启动炸药
I'm arming the explosives right now.
你们得立刻撤离
You have to get out.
什么 等等 你不能那样做
What? Wait, no, you can't do that.
来不及 你明知我们来不及
There isn't time. You know there isn't time.
我们需要十分钟才能撤离爆炸区
It will take ten minutes to get clear.
蒙提斯
Montes!
抱歉了 各位
Sorry, guys.
蒙提斯 蒙提斯 别这样
Montes! Montes, don't do it!
怎么回事
What was that?
坍塌
Landslide!
我无法绕过它 只能直接穿越
I can't get ahead of it. I'm gonna have to go through.
各位 发生什么事了
Guys? What's happening?
读数显示温跃层破裂
I'm reading a thermocline breach.
有东西在上面炸开一个大洞
Something's ripped a giant hole in it.
重组推进器 我们只能这样了
Rerouting the thrusters. This is all we've got.
垂直控制功能失灵
Vertical control is down.
液压系统失去回应
Hydraulics are non-responsive.
我们被卡死了
We're pinned.
我们来搞定
Coming in.
-稳住潜艇 -好
-  Hold us steady. -  Yeah.
九溟 在下方六十度
Jiuming. Sixty degrees down.
前方两呎处
Two feet forward.
九溟
Jiuming!
快驶离
Go, go, go!
全速前进 全速前进
Full thrust! Full thrust!
九溟
Jiuming!
不
No!
遥测数据归零
There's no telemetry.
潜艇一号 潜艇二号 收到请回答
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
仪表上什么都扫不到
We've got nothing here.
继续努力 DJ 洁丝 立刻准备救援潜艇
Keep trying, DJ. Jess, prep the rescue sub. Stat.
到底发生什么事
Ugh, what happened?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们怎么知道他们是否还活着
How do we know if they're still alive?
准备救援潜艇
Prep the rescue vehicle.
潜艇一号 潜艇二号 收到请回答
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
加油啊 乔纳斯
Come on, Jonas.
玫盈
Meiying.
- Meiying.
发生什么事了
What happened?
我们遭受重创
Took a nasty hit.
九溟舅舅呢
Uncle Jiuming?
九溟舅舅在哪
Where's Uncle Jiuming?
-他在哪里  -我们联系不上他
- Where is he? - We can't raise him.
喂 我们依序解决每个问题
Hey. We work the problems one by one.
先解决眼前的事 然后再应付下一件
We do what's in front of us... and then we do the next thing.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
麦克
Mac!
救援潜艇无法运作
The rescue sub isn't working.
电池阵列被特意短路 看起来像是蓄意破坏
The battery array was deliberately shorted out. It looks like sabotage.
这怎么可能
How's that possible?
这里不是管制区 还有30个工作人员
This isn't a secure area. There are 30 people who work here.
要多久才能修好
Well, how long to fix it?
控制板坏了 麦克 修不好了
It's the control boards, Mac. There is no fixing it.
-再试试 -我们情况如何
Try it now. What's our status?
通讯和温控都失灵
No comms, no heat.
还在快速流失氧气
We're losing air fast.
这样行不通的
This isn't working.
把我额外储备的氧气也汇入
Flood in my extra O2.
已经汇入了
Already done.
我还有最后一个办法
I've got one last idea.
将电路绕过温控系统
Route the power through the heating cell.
联系上潜艇一号了 麦克 联系上潜艇一号了
I got Dive 1. Mac, I got Dive 1.
乔纳斯
Jonas?
很高兴听到你的声音 麦克
Good to hear your voice, Mac.
我更高兴听到你的 兄弟
Not as good as it is to hear yours, brother.
情况如何
Talk to me.
很不妙
It ain't good.
几乎每个系统都失灵了 我们正快速流失氧气
Almost every system is down, and we're losing air fast.
我们会先换上紧急潜水机甲 但需要有人来接我们
We'll get into the emergency dive suits... and we're gonna need a ride up.
乔纳斯 这点我们目前做不到
Jonas... it's not gonna be possible.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
电池阵列导致救援潜艇的控制板短路
The battery array. It shorted out the control board in the rescue sub.
我们目前正在调查
We're investigating it now.
乔纳斯
Jonas?
乔纳斯 你能听到吗
Jonas, can you hear me?
乔纳斯 我们无法去救你们
Jonas, we can't get to you.
那我们就用走的
We're gonna walk.
我们回头穿越海沟 前往海底基地
We're gonna walk back across the trench. Make it into that sea floor station.
我们要进去 然后再回到海平面
And we're gonna get inside. And then we're gonna get to the surface.
那些潜水机甲顶多配备两小时氧气
Those suits have two hours of air tops.
专为短暂的舱外工作设计
They're only designed for brief extravehicular work.
我们会缓慢平稳地前进 没问题的
We'll go slow and steady. They'll hold.
距离有三公里
It's three kilometers.
在海底你们毫无防备
You'll be defenseless out there.
麦克 不然你要我怎么办
What do you want from me, Mac?
目前条件如此 所以只能这样做
This is what we got, and this is what we're gonna do.
一半的组员已经死了
Half our team is dead,
我不要再失去另一半
and I'm not losing the other half.
开始潜水机甲初始化
Beginning suit initialization.
关节促动器运作正常
Joint actuators functioning.
超声波讯号通讯上线
Ultrasonic signal communications online.
初始化完成
Initialization complete.
我们要抛下潜艇一号了 麦克
Abandoning Dive 1, Mac.
无线电通讯无法传回海平面 所以我们要断讯了
The radios won't relay to the surface, so we're going dark.
到基地后再跟你通话
Talk to you on the other side.
祝你们好运 乔纳斯
Godspeed, Jonas.
紧急逃生系统启动
Emergency escape initiated.
（海沟：深度两万五千呎）
妈啊
Hey. Whoa!
我差点杀了你
Almost killed you.
你来这里干嘛
The hell are you doing?
来拯救你
Saving your ass.
然后再走回那个基地
And walking back to that station.
那你是来干嘛的
What are you doing?
先拯救你 然后再走回那个基地
Saving your ass. And walking back to that station.
-时间不多了 -我们走吧
- Don't have much time. - Let's get going.
舅
Jiu.
舅 我以为你…
Uncle, I thought you--
想甩了我 没那么容易
You're not going to get rid of me that easily.
喂 喂 让我检查一下
Hey. Hey. Let me check.
氧气剩余…
Air left...
你得冷静下来 不然会缺氧的 兰斯
Hey, you need to calm down or you're gonna run out of oxygen, Lance.
我无法冷静
I don't think i can.
把这想象成角色扮演
Think of it as cosplay.
或者在玩漆弹对战
Or we could be paintballing.
像是终极版的团建活动那样
Like the ultimate team-building exercise.
我们要在巨齿鲨 无暇顾及我们时尽快闪远
We need to cover distance while the megs are still occupied.
距离目的地三公里
Three kilometers to destination.
我赞成尽量远离巨齿鲨
Away from the megs is fine by me.
我们是个强大的团队
We're a strong group.
我们做得到的
We can do this.
太神奇了
Amazing.
由大自然免费提供的照明
Lighting courtesy of Mother Nature.
太不可思议了 周围四处都是新物种
It's incredible, there are new species all around us.
喂 你们看
Hey. Look.
看这个 好漂亮
Look at this. It's beautiful.
你好 我会发光的…
Hello, my little biolum--
快把蛇拿走 有一条蛇
There's a snake! There's a snake!
把这个怪物从我头上拿下来
Get this monster off my head!
别再乱摸东西了
No touching stuff.
是他先开始的
He started it.
其余人员都撤离基地
Everyone clear the station.
DJ 乔纳斯出发多久了
DJ, what's our time on Jonas?
断讯后已过了41分钟
Forty-one minutes since they went dark.
他们最快还要一小时才能走到
At best, it'll take another hour for them to cover the distance.
听好了
Listen up.
我们知道海沟里有某种非法活动
We know there's some kind of rogue operation in the trench.
现在还有混蛋插手这里的作业
Now, some bastard's got his fingers in our operation here.
那艘潜艇肯定是被破坏了 所以我们基地有内奸
That sub was definitely sabotaged, so we've got a mole on the station.
DJ 我要你调出过去24小时内
DJ, I want you to pull all surveillance footage
舱区的所有监控画面
from the sub bay for the last 24 hours.
洁丝 清查组员人事档案 寻找任何疑点
Jess, run the personnel files on the crew, look for anything suspect.
抓住这些混蛋 但同时小心自身安全
We're gonna get these sons of bitches, but we have to watch our own backs.
随时要有人留守指挥中心 懂吗
One of us mans the DCC at all times, understood?
好的
Yes.
是只有我这样想
Is it just me,
还是在海底健行三公里真的很累
or does walking three kilometers underwater sound like hard work?
这肯定不在我的愿望清单上
It certainly wasn't on my to-do list.
小章鱼
Baby octopi.
好多种颜色 真不可思议
So many colors. That's incredible.
有人想玩游戏吗
Anybody wanna play a game?
游戏
A game?
这不是游戏
This isn't a game.
她的意思是让我们别胡思乱想
She means to keep our minds occupied.
现在我已经在胡思乱想了
Right now, my mind is pretty damn occupied.
这有只 有只 是…
There's a... there's a... It's...
兰斯
Lance?
是什么东西
What was it?
-我没看到 -兰斯在哪里
-  I didn't see. -  Where's Lance?
是巨齿鲨吗
Is it a meg?
他出事了 我很确定
Some... something's happened to him. I know it.
兰斯
Lance?
不 不要
No. Oh, no.
我们得继续前进
We have to keep moving.
不 我们不能把他留在这里
No, we... We can't just leave him out there.
我们需要找到他
We need to find him!
拜托 九溟
Please, Jiuming.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
他已经死了
He's gone.
芮格斯 掩护我们后方 有任何动静立刻开枪
Rigas, cover our six. Shoot anything that moves.
包在我身上
You bet your ass I will.
通讯系统上线
Comms online.
发生什么事了
What happened to you?
玛纳一号组员无意间发现我们基地
The Mana One crew stumbled upon our station.
我炸了个坍塌把他们干掉了
I took them out with a landslide.
事情真的太失控了
Okay, this is... this is out of control.
你授权我采取任何手段来保护行动
You authorized me to do whatever's necessary to protect our operation.
不
No.
他们没死 现在正步行前往基地
They're not dead. They are walking right now to the station.
若他们成功抵达
If they get there,
我们就玩完了
we are screwed.
取道山谷的话还剩一公里要走
There's still a kilometer to go, straight through that valley,
而且没有生物光来掩护我们
and we don't have the bioluminescence to cover us.
我们的行迹将完全暴露其中
We're going to be totally exposed out there.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
我们的氧气只够我们直线穿越
We only have enough air to go straight through.
将照明亮度调低
Let's keep our lights on low spectrum.
对 我们不想引来任何巨齿鲨
Yeah. We don't want to attract the megs.
距离目的地一公里
One kilometer to destination.
回报氧气剩余量
O2 check?
65%
65%.
50%
50.
26%
26%.
这绝对不够
It's not gonna be enough.
看着我 看着我
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
看着我 好吗 保持专注
Look at me, okay? Focus, okay?
你能做到 记住受训内容
You can do this. Remember the training.
声纳上有什么吗
Anything on sonar?
我扫到一些东西 就在范围的边缘
I got something, right at the edge of my range.
不断地进进出出
Keeps going in and out.
它们在跟踪我们
Stalking us.
迫近警报
Proximity alert.
是什么东西
What is it?
只是一群鱼
It's just a shoal of fish.
大家保持冷静
Stay calm, everyone.
-你还好吗  -还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
继续前进
Keep moving.
喂 麦克
Ayo, Mac.
监控画面半点不剩 内容都被删除了
We got jack on the security footage. Somebody deleted it.
舱区的画面
For the sub bay?
整个该死的基地都被删了
For the whole damn station.
他们很缜密 但并非无所不知
They're good, but they don't know everything.
我们还会将加密备份上链卫星
There's a satellite uplink with an encrypted backup.
我要去伺服器室 看看能否下载
I'm gonna go to the server room, see if I can pull it down.
过多久了
Time?
1小时50分 他们很快就要没氧气了
One hour, 50. They'll be out of air soon.
我正在扫描所有频道 但还没音讯
I'm scanning all channels, but nothing yet.
快到了 大约还剩四百米
That's it. Maybe 400 meters.
警告 进入备用氧气量
Warning. Entering oxygen reserves.
你做得到
You can do this.
-好吗  -好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我得到读数
I'm getting a reading.
我们右边有很多动静
Many contacts to our right.
并快速迫近
Coming in fast.
什么 是巨齿鲨吗
What, megs?
不 更小也更快
No. Smaller. Faster.
大家立刻前往基地 快点
Everybody make it to the station! Go, move!
-警告 氧气剩余量低 -加油
Warning. Oxygen level low. Come on.
-快点 -我要没气了
- Come on. - I'm out of air.
它们正在越过海脊
They're coming over the ridge!
那是什么东西
What are those things?
太远了
It's too far.
我们得采举防御行动
We need to make a stand!
转身迎战
Turn and fight!
滚开
Come on!
-玫盈 -救命 射它们的头
- Meiying! - Help! Shoot their head!
-玫盈 -舅舅
- Meiying! - Uncle!
我抓住你了
I've got you!
抓紧我
Hold on!
它们正在咬穿潜水机甲
They're biting through the suit.
玫盈
Meiying!
不 不要
No. No.
坚持住 寇蒂斯
Hold on, Curtis!
太多只了 我们毫无胜算
Too many! We don't have a chance!
大家退后
Everybody stay back!
继续前进
Keep going!
九溟
Jiuming!
别无选择了
There's no choice.
你真的很想死 是吧
You really want to die, don't you?
得赶快进入气闸舱
Gotta make it to the airlock!
警告 低氧量
Warning. Low air.
-没用的 我只会拖累你 -低氧量
- It's no use I'm holding you back. - Low air.
就快到了 你能做到
- It's not too far. - You can make it!
警告 低氧量
Warning. Low air.
氧气耗尽
Air depleted.
舅舅
Uncle!
面罩即将失效
Visor failure imminent.
九溟
Jiuming!
好 我们得前进 我们别无选择
Okay. We gotta go. We don't have a choice.
它绕回来了
He's coming back around!
-老天 -进去 进去
-  Oh, God! -  Go, go, go!
我们得越权控制
We have to do the override.
加油 快点
Come on, hurry up.
芮格斯 加油
Rigas, come on!
你做得到 快进来
You can do it. Get in!
关上门
Shut the door!
寇蒂斯 没事的
Curtis, you'll be okay.
机甲即将内爆
Suit implosion imminent.
-快好了 快好了 -老天
- Almost there. Almost there! - Oh, my God.
要内爆了
It's gonna implode.
快给舱房减压
Depressurize the room!
不 不 不要
No, no, no.
-内爆 -不要
- No!
可恶
Son of a bitch!
我讨厌那些鬼东西
I hate these things!
喂 芮格斯
Hey, Rigas.
尽快收拾好心情
Let's try to keep it together.
我们尚未脱离困境
We ain't out of the woods yet.
芮格斯
Rigas.
人都上哪去了
Where is everybody?
那是什么味道
What is that smell?
潜水员
Divers.
没人在家
Nobody home.
我来负责守门
I'll cover the door.
运行这基地的人是敌非友
Whoever's running this is not our friend.
我们需要尽快联系玛纳一号 你做得到吗
We need to contact Mana One ASAP. Think you can handle it?
可以 当然可以
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
他们到底在开采什么
What is this that they're mining?
不管是什么 他们都用这些容器运到海平面上
Whatever it is, they're sending it up to the surface with these pods.
稀土金属
Mmm. Rare earth metals.
被用于超导体 航太工程与量子计算
They're used in superconductors, aerospace and quantum computing.
光这一箱可能就价值十亿
This box alone could be a billion dollars.
十亿美元吗
"Billion" with a "B?"
对
Yes.
玛纳一号
- Mana One.
乔纳斯 通讯上线了
Jonas. Comms are live.
请回话
Come in.
这是乔纳斯 听得到吗
It's Jonas. Getting this?
天啊 你还活着
Hey, you're alive.
你们情况如何
What's your status?
我们失去了兰斯 莎尔和寇蒂斯
We lost Lance, Sal, and Curtis.
现在抵达海底基地
We're at the station.
这是一个非法采矿作业
It's a rogue mining operation.
下面有人吗
Is there anyone down there?
目前为止我们还没看到
Not that we've seen so far.
他们已经渗透了玛纳一号
They've infiltrated Mana One.
救援潜艇遭到破坏
The rescue sub was sabotaged.
-是谁做的  -我们正在调查 但先听我说
- By who? - We're working on it. But check this out.
我刚才在检视先前扫描基地的影片
I was going over the video of when you went over that station before.
你们看北边
Look at the north side.
看起来像紧急逃生舱
Looks like emergency escape pods.
是我们现在位置的另一端
It's the opposite side from where we are.
这里感觉死气沉沉的
Feels dead in here.
跟紧点
Stay close.
这些是我设计的
These are my designs.
他们怎么会有这个
How do they have this?
看来就是这里了
Looks like this is it.
数到三
On three.
三
Three.
-再试一次 -没用的
-  Again. - It's not gonna work.
你们先请
After you.
这才像话嘛
Ah, this is more like it.
快点打开个逃生舱然后闪人
Let's crack open a pod and get out of here.
这里什么都没有
Nothing here.
这些控制板都失灵了
These controls ain't working.
我们得先关闭舱门
We need to close the hatch.
我来吧
On it.
各位 不是我关的
Guys, that wasn't me.
乔纳斯 既然你来了 我们就摊开来谈吧
Jonas, now that I have you here, we need to talk candidly.
我已完全掌控基地 并锁死这舱房
I have full control of the station, and I've locked down this room.
洁丝
Jess?
你的性命掌握在我手中
Your life is in my hands.
你在干嘛 洁丝
What are you doing, Jess?
这些人是你的朋友
These are your friends.
你们一起共事好多年了
They've been with you for years.
我知道事实很伤人
I know it hurts.
之所以跟你谈 是因为希望我们能站在同一边
And we're talking because I'd prefer we were on the same side.
要是所有人都赚那么多钱 就没意思了
All making so much money, it ceases to have meaning.
你想用钱收买我们
You're offering us money?
我们的三个朋友都被你害死了
Three of our friends are dead because of you.
你以为我会忘记这点
You think I'm gonna forget about that?
不不不 那是第一个逃生舱
No, no, no, no, no! That's the first escape pod!
可恶
Son of a bitch!
芮格斯 芮格斯 你可以救下玫盈
Rigas? Rigas, you can save Meiying.
拿起那把鱼枪 往乔纳斯的心脏射
Take that speargun and shoot Jonas in the heart.
别开枪打他
Don't shoot him.
来吧
Do it.
快点
Go ahead.
只有这样才能让玫盈活下去
It's the only way Meiying survives.
来吧
Do it.
芮格斯
Rigas!
开枪
Do it!
-开枪 -不 对不起
- Do it! - No. I'm sorry.
对不起 我做不到 我做不到
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I can't. I can't. I can't.
那是最后一个逃生舱
That was the last pod.
就跟你说那招行不通
I told you that wouldn't work.
让我跟他们谈
Put me on.
很抱歉 不得不走到这一步
Oh, sorry it had to come to this.
所以…
So...
我们会在一周内恢复开采
we'll be back at work in a week,
使用你们的技术 来获取任何我们想要的东西
using your technology to take whatever we want.
你的研究所将成为我们的跳板
Your institute'll be a platform that we use
在未来数十年继续掠夺海洋
to plunder the ocean for decades.
你会有报应的
Karma will get you.
少跟我抱怨什么生态系统
And before you start whining about the ecosystem,
鬼才在乎 我们将获利数十亿美元
who cares? We'll make billions.
而且没人会看到我们造成的破坏
And no one is going to see the damage we do.
你闭嘴
Shut up!
洁丝 我已派遣善后小组前往玛纳一号
Jess, I've already dispatched a clean-up crew to Mana One.
了结此事
Finish this.
（洪氾区）
我们要如何打开门
How do we open the door?
若能切断与海平面的通讯讯号
If we could cut the comm link to the surface...
她就无法操纵一切
she couldn't control anything.
但那在之前第一个舱房 而且我们无法打开这扇门
But it's back in the first room, and there's no getting through this door.
这个气闸舱仍然能开启
This airlock still works!
为何要穿越气闸舱 已没有逃生舱了
Why would you go through the airlock? There's no pod.
我会游到当初进来的气闸舱 并进行越权控制
I'll swim to the airlock where we came in and do the override.
你没有潜水机甲 这怎么能行
You have no suit. How could it work?
水在压力下不会压缩
Water doesn't compress under pressure,
所以若他能强迫海水进入鼻窦腔
so if he can force water in his sinus cavities,
那他在昏倒之前 或许可以存活30到60秒
he could survive 30, maybe 60 seconds before he passes out.
这是有可能做到的
- It is possible.
我们依序解决每个问题
We work the problems one by one.
先解决眼前的事 然后再应付下一件
We do what's in front of us, then we do the next thing.
若有任何人能完成这件事
If anyone can do this,
那肯定是你
it's you.
他不会被压力挤扁吗
Won't he be crushed by the pressure?
事情不是那样的
It doesn't work like that.
水里的鱼也没穿金属机甲 对吧
You don't see fish wearing metal suits, do you?
重点在于空气 它在压力下做出反应
It's about air. It reacts under pressure.
所以他才必须把空气从鼻窦中排出来
And that's why he has to blow it out of his sinuses.
喂 环保狂人
Hey there, tree hugger.
乔纳斯泰勒 生态战士
Jonas Taylor, eco-warrior,
为崇高的使命而战
fighting the good fight.
结果你猜怎么了
Well, guess what?
你输了
You lost.
我在马尼拉监狱蹲了两年
I spent two years in a Manila prison
因为你和你的生态怪咖同伙 害我们的船被扣押
after you and your eco-freak buddies had our ship seized.
我每天都在想你
I thought about you every single day.
你甚至不记得我了 对吗
You don't even remember me, do you?
没印象
No?
蒙提斯
Montes.
这世上有数百万个混帐
There's a million scumbags in this world.
很难记得每一个
It's hard to keep track of all of 'em.
我不行了
I don't think I can make it!
抓紧 抓紧 没事
You can do it. It's okay.
我们要死了
We're going to die!
没事 没事
It's ok, it's ok.
（主锁越权控制）
（确认越权控制 确认）
玫盈
Meiying!
善后小组即将抵达玛纳一号
Clean up crew approaching Mana One.
总算到了 我们处于警戒状态
About time. We are on alert.
员工们都被监禁在自己寝室里
Everyone confined to their quarters.
我们需要全面控制玛纳一号 并解决任何威胁
We need to get control of Mana One and dispose of any liabilities.
发生了什么紧急情况
What's the emergency?
我找到了监控备份
I got into the security backup.
你看这个
Look at this.
是洁丝破坏了救援潜艇
Jess disabled the rescue sub.
-什么  -你看
- What? - Watch.
她看起来像在修理 对吧  但不是 等着
Like she could be repairing it, right? But no, wait.
这是蒙提斯的潜艇
It's Montes' sub.
我们要开着它离开
That's our ride out of here.
液压装置外泄
There's a leak in the hydraulics.
掠食者防御系统也失灵了
Predator countermeasures are down.
我们绝对无法逃离巨齿鲨的包抄
We'll never make it past the megs.
我们需要障眼法
We need a distraction.
点亮基地 巨齿鲨会转而攻击它
Light up the station. The megs will attack it.
对 然后一并杀死我们
Yeah. And kill us.
如果我们够快就不会
Not if we're fast enough.
九溟
Jiuming!
-喂 芮格斯 -是
-  Hey, Rigas. - Yep?
那一刻 我还以为你会杀了我
For a moment, I thought you were gonna kill me back there.
因为她要求我朝你的心脏开枪
Well, she did say to shoot you in the heart.
但我很清楚你没有心
And I know for a fact you ain't got one of those.
你俩再慢点吧
Thank you for working.
你得关上舱门 乔纳斯
Gotta close the hatch, Jonas.
不然我们都会死
We're all gonna die.
他会回来的
He's gonna make it.
不 他不会
No, he's not.
-他会成功的 -不 我们必须关闭舱门
- He's gonna make it. - No! We have to close the hatch!
关门 乔纳斯
Close it! Jonas!
我回来了
I'm here!
是他
That's him!
刚才真惊险
That was close.
太惊险了
Too close.
你应该关上舱门的
You should have shut the hatch.
对 但玫盈会杀了我
Yeah. Meiying would have killed me.
但你有考虑过
You thought about it, though.
对 我们有考虑过
Yeah. We thought about it.
对吧 芮格斯
Didn't we, Rigas?
你闭嘴吧
Shut up.
只有一点点
Just a little bit.
孙子
Very funny.
炸药
Explosives?
看看这个
Check this out.
你看还有什么
Look what else.
那会造成问题吗
Is that gonna be a problem?
那是温跃层上的破口
It's a hole in the thermal layer.
一定是采矿爆炸时造成的
It must have been caused by the mining explosions.
最终会自动闭合
It will seal up eventually.
最终
Eventually?
对 在一个小时内
Yeah. Within an hour.
巨齿鲨能跟着我们穿过去吗
Can the megs follow us through?
希望不能
I hope not.
男士们 我不想伤害你们 但我需要你们出来
Boys, I don't want to harm you, but I do need you to come out of this room.
是洁丝 她带了三个士兵
It's Jess. She's got three soldiers.
好 该动手了
Yeah. It's go time.
拿着这个
Take this.
-什么鬼东西  -这是电击棒
- The hell is this? - It's a Taser.
开门
Open up.
他们试图杀掉乔纳斯 肯定也会杀了我们
They tried to kill Jonas, they're definitely gonna kill us.
好吧 听着 计画如下
Okay, listen. Here's the plan.
数到三后 你把门打开 我会朝他们喷防狼喷雾
On the count of three, you'll open the door and I'mma pepper spray 'em.
然后你关门 稍待片刻
Right, and you'll shut the door and you're gonna wait.
再出去使用电击棒
Then go out there and use the Taser.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
不 麦克 不要
No, Mac, no!
不 麦克…
No, Mac...
好痛 好痛
It burns! It burns!
抱歉了
I'm sorry!
睡觉时间到
Sleepy time.
那是什么
What's that?
（一号监控器）
麻烦
Trouble.
这样信心满满地乱闯是很好
So, we're walking fast and with a lot of determination, which is great.
但我们的计画到底是什么
But what exactly is the plan here?
他们有武器 而我们没有
They're armed and we're not.
好吧 那你想干嘛
All righty. So what are you thinking?
你又想干嘛
What are you thinking?
你和我去找麦克和DJ
You and I find Mac and DJ.
芮格斯 尽量收集物资 再找一艘救生船 我们才能离开
Rigas, grab what you can. Secure a Zodiac so we can get off this thing.
太赞了
Rock and roll.
玫盈跟着你比较安全
Safest if Meiying goes with you.
我会用生命来保护她
I'll protect her with my life.
我也会用生命保护她
And I'll protect her with mine.
不行
No.
走吧
Let's go.
我都跟你说了要等一下再出门
I told you to wait before you went out that door.
-眼睛还好吗  -眼睛爆痛
- How's your eyes? - My eye stings.
如果我们能爬上通讯阵列
If we climb up to the communications array,
就能绕过指挥中心 打电话求助
we can bypass the DCC and we can call for help.
我们该怎么说
What are we supposed to say?
恐怖攻击事件
Uh... terrorist action?
-对 很好 恐攻事件 -对 恐攻事件
- Yeah, good. Terrorist action. - Yeah, terrorist action.
-好吧 -你有更好的主意吗
-  Okay. - You got a better idea?
不准动
-  Freeze!
糟了
Oh, no.
DJ DJ
DJ! DJ!
搞什么
What the hell?
就是这样 宝贝 看我多厉害
Wow! Yeah, baby! Get some!
-喂 -跑 麦克 快跑
- Hey. - Run, Mac! Run!
快点 快点
Go, go, go!
散开 找到他们
Spread out! Find 'em.
你携带电击棒 现在还会游泳
You got Tasers? Now you can swim?
突然间 你就像蝙蝠侠一样到处乱窜
All of a sudden you run around like you're frickin' Batman.
没错
Hell yeah.
上次之后 你们都求我回来
After last time, y'all begged me to come back.
“DJ 我们是一家人 DJ”
"DJ, oh, we family, DJ."
“DJ 我们需要你” 好 好事 我答应 但我并不傻
"DJ, we need you." Yeah, all right. Bet. But I ain't stupid.
我开始锻炼 学会如何战斗跟游泳
I trained up, I learned how to fight, I learned how to swim,
而且出门一定要带上我的求生包
and I will never go anywhere without my survival pack.
-求生包  -对
- Survival pack? - Yeah.
你瞧
Check this out.
来吧 宝贝 过来
Mmm-hmm. Come here, baby. Come here.
砰
Bam.
对 我甚至像电影《大白鲨2》那样
Yeah, I even made poison-tipped bullets,
制作了带毒子弹
just like Jaws 2.
来吧 DJ 我们走
Come on, DJ! Let's go, let's go.
这太扯了
This is insane.
不准动 混蛋
Freeze, assholes.
对 不准动
Yeah, freeze.
你能搞定吗
You got this?
刚才真是不走运
That was some unfortunate shit back there.
不要 拜托 别开枪
No, please! Don't shoot!
我知道你们在找我和乔纳斯
I know you're looking for me and Jonas.
但我相信你们听不懂中文
I also know you don't speak Chinese,
我说那么多中文因为你们听不懂 为了吸引你们的注意力
but I'm speaking it to distract you guys,
因为我的朋友们要背后袭击你们
because my friend is about to attack you from behind.
什么
What?
蠢蛋
sucker.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
你想得美 麦克
Wishful thinking, Mac.
原来是鼻中膈弯曲先生
If it ain't the deviated septum.
有船正在离开
Boat's leaving.
目前情况如何
What's our status?
B小队正在赶过来 预计10分钟后抵达
Bravo team are inbound. ETA, ten minutes.
太好了
Excellent.
你来这里做什么
Uh, what are you doing here?
-你还好吗  -还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
乔纳斯在玛纳一号上
Jonas is on Mana One.
我们现在需要封锁此处
We need to lock this place down now.
全面搜查基地
Search the station top to bottom.
将基地员工关在寝室 其余的格杀勿论
Secure personnel in their quarters, kill anyone else.
快去 去啊
Go! Go!
我的天
Oh, my God.
各位 我们有大麻烦了
Uh, guys? We've got a big problem.
我们追踪到三只 在破口关闭前逃脱的巨齿鲨
We tracked three megs that escaped before the breach closed.
我们需要为此准备好一个说辞
We're gonna need a good cover story for this.
那应该不难
Well, that shouldn't be hard.
大家都知道 乔纳斯和九溟有多胆大妄为
Everyone knows Jonas and Jiuming were reckless.
不 我们需要一个英雄
No, we need a hero.
从这场意外的悲剧中挺身而出
Like, someone to emerge from this unforeseeable tragedy,
担起领导研究所的位置
who can step into a leadership position at the Institute.
洁丝 你准备好要升职了吗
Jess, are you ready for promotion?
很感谢你的信任
I appreciate your confidence.
洁丝
Jess!
它是从温跃层破口逃出来的 但你大可放心
It's from the thermocline breach. But you can relax.
这地方百分百防鲨
This place? Meg-proof.
乔纳斯原本一直很担心这点
I mean, Jonas was always afraid of this,
但我认为只要有追踪器 和武装直升机 就能轻松解决
but I think, between trackers and gunships, we can solve the problem
并凭藉高超的公关技巧扭转舆论
and come out the other side with a significant positive PR spin.
对 我已经着手进行
Yeah, I'm on it.
我也在考虑…
I was also thinking...
现在怎么办
What now?
这是唯一的出路 我们必须接受
It's our only way off. We have to take it.
但那艘船不足以载我们返回大陆
But that thing doesn't have the range to get us to the mainland.
你担心上不了岸 那前一百码呢
You're worried about the destination? What about the first hundred yards?
我们估计到时就挂点了
That's where we goin' die.
我们慢慢划船
We paddle out slow.
不开引擎 维持最小动静
No engines. Minimal motion.
我们就不会看起来像食物
We won't look like food.
等我们划远后 再放手一搏
When we're clear, we make a run for it. Huh?
我们开始吧
Let's do it.
我仍然认为我们看起来像食物
I still think we look like food.
大家安静
Shh. Quiet, everyone.
慢慢划桨
Paddle slowly.
这感觉令人不快地熟悉
This feels unpleasantly familiar.
希望结果会比上次好
I just hope it goes better than last time.
上次怎么了
What happened last time?
你不会想知道的
You don't wanna know.
它来了
Here he comes.
快点 快点
Go, go, go!
千万别让他们活着回来
Let's not bring 'em back alive.
你知道怎么开这东西 对吧
You do know how to drive this thing, right?
熄火 立刻关掉引擎
Stop! Stop the engine right now.
不然会吸引巨齿鲨过来
Or you will attract the megs.
好的 不要动
Okay. Be still.
不要有任何动作
- No motion whatsoever.
我锁定他们了
I have the shot.
开枪
Take it.
-趴下 -快点 执行任务
- Get down! -  Mate, do your job.
-快开枪 -没那么容易
- Take the bloody shot. - It's not easy as it looks.
它杀了他们 它吃掉了他们
He got 'em! He ate 'em!
它吃掉整条船
He ate the whole boat!
发生什么事了
What happened?
洁丝死了
Jess is dead.
-什么  -我们控制住玛纳一号
- What? - We stabilized Mana One
但泰勒和张逃脱了
but Taylor and Zhang have escaped.
你希望我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
搞定一切 杀了他们
Fix it! Kill them!
只要能做到 条件任你开
You do this, you write your own ticket.
保证你一生富贵
You are set for life.
好
Okay.
他们只可能逃往几个地方
There's only a couple places they could make it to.
你在哭吗 蒙提斯
- Are you crying, Montes? -
（小心炸药）
有巨齿鲨的踪迹吗
Any sign of the megs?
没有
Negative.
这东西绝对行不通的
There's no way this thing's gonna work.
它会行得通
It's gonna work.
你炸死自己的机会 都比炸死巨齿鲨还高
Bloke, you got more chance of blowing up yourself than one of the megs.
至少我不会被吃掉
At least I won't get eaten.
说得对
Ha, I hear that.
乔纳斯 能帮我做一支吗
Jo, can you make me one?
包在我身上 麦克
I got you covered, Mac.
我们必须想办法警告群众
We have to find a way to warn people.
以防巨齿鲨向岸边移动
In case the megs move towards land.
在东南方60公里处有一个岛屿
There's an island 60 klicks southeast of us.
它被列为有人居住
It's listed as inhabited.
有谁居住
Inhabited by who?
岛名翻译起来差不多是…
The name more or less translates to...
欢乐岛
Fun Island.
Fun Island?
（欢乐岛）
好耶
Yeah!
欢迎来到欢乐岛 我们的度假村应有尽有
Welcome to Fun Island. Our resort has everything.
餐厅 超美味
The restaurant, amazing.
迪斯可舞厅 棒极了
The disco, incredible.
还有我们的水疗中心 舒适无比
And our spa, to die for.
我的天啊
OMG.
这是我们的招牌菜 海鲜惊喜
It's our special dish. Seafood Surprise!
天啊 我真不知要从哪开始
Wow! I wouldn't know where to start.
好吧 千万不要错过烤鲨鱼
Well, just don't miss out on the grilled shark.
皮聘 皮聘
Pippin! Pippin!
皮聘
Pippin!
-妈啊 那是什么  -皮聘
- Whoa, what is that? -  Pippin!
它们在逃离什么
What are they running from?
你是菜鸟吗
Your first time at the rodeo?
在你出生前我就跟你爸合作
I worked with your dad since before you were born.
他没给过我这种气受
I never had this kind of trouble from him.
能不能把手机放下
Can you put your phone down?
好不容易出来一回 这憋多久了
After all these hard years we're finally on vacation,
能不能爽一下
savor the moment.
对 我也会对他大吼大叫
Yeah, and I yelled at him too.
刚五分钟 就四百多个赞
I've already got 400 likes.
我的妈呀
我身处天堂 你却要毁了一切
I'm sitting in paradise and you are ruining it!
谁会干这种事 毁了别人的天堂
Who does that? Who... ruins paradise for other people?
嗨 宝贝
Hey, baby.
想帮我在背上抹点油吗
Wanna rub some oil on my back?
不要吗
No?
那前面呢
How 'bout my front?
恶心
Ew.
（距欢乐岛5公里 距温跃层破口70公里）
过来
Come over.
什么呀
What?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
瑶瑶
Yaoyao...
愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
快去找戒指啊 笨蛋
Find it, idiot!
你等会啊
Wait!
找到了没
Have you found it?
喂
Hey.
瑶瑶
Yaoyao.
瑶瑶 瑶瑶
Yaoyao! Yaoyao!
那看起来不太妙
This doesn't look good.
芮格斯 快载我们过去
Rigas, get us there fast!
切断手机上链讯号
Kill the cell phone uplink.
这是我们公关的好机会
There's a lot of exposure for us on this.
尽快解决乔纳斯和他的队员
Take care of Jonas and his team quickly,
别闹出动静
and quietly.
大家快上岸
Everybody out of the water!
-鲨鱼 有鲨鱼 -回到海滩上
-  Shark! Shark! -  Get back on the beach!
快上岸
Get out of the water!
大家快回海滩上…
Get back on the beach, every...
电信通讯已截断 结束
Mobile comms are down. Over.
伙计们 收到了吗
You copy, guys?
鳄鱼
Crocodile!
那是什么鬼
What is that?
-快点 快点 -回到直升机上
-  Move, move! - Get into the chopper.
立刻送她去
Now! Go with her!
大家快上岸
Everybody out!
-鲨鱼 -鲨鱼
Shark! Shark!
回去 不要下水
- Go back! - Don't go into the water!
水里有鲨鱼
There's a shark!
快上海滩 回去
Get on the beach! Go back!
你必须去拯救他们
We have to save them.
-我不会丢下你一人 -手机没讯号了
- I'm not leaving ya. - Cell phone's down.
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
-没有讯号 -别无选择
-  No signal. - There's no choice.
-她说得对 -手机没有讯号
- She's right. -  We got no signal, guys.
你们两个 想办法打电话求救
Hey, you two! Find a way to call for help.
让大家知道发生什么事了
Let everyone know what happened.
快点 快点 往这边走
Come on! Come on! This way! This way!
你去躲起来 看到那个救生塔吗
You're gonna hide. See that lifeguard tower?
-有 -你去那里 然后待在里面
- Yeah. - You go there and you stay there.
这次千万不要再像以前那样
This is not one of those things where I tell you to do something,
表面答应 然后任意行事 懂吗
you say "yes," and then you do whatever you want. Understand?
懂了
Yes.
你没在敷衍我吧
You're not messing with me?
没有
No.
若我需要担心你 就无法全力发挥
I can't do what I need to do if I'm worried about you.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
答应我你会回来
Promise me you'll come back.
你知道我爱你
You know I love you.
糟了
Oh, shit.
桑尼 去查看一下
Sonny. Check that out.
喂 兄弟 你有手机吗
Hey, yo, my man. You got a phone?
大家都在躲避什么
What's everyone running from?
那是什么声音
What the hell was that?
三只巨齿鲨
Three megs.
我们三人 每人骑一台水上摩托车
Three of us. We each grab a jet ski.
让它们来追我们 远离人群 游向外海
Get them to chase it away from these people and out to sea.
然后我们再用鱼叉攻击它们
Then we harpoon them.
你是指那些东贴西补 不知会致命还是索命的鱼叉
Oh, you mean with those jerry-rigged, maybe-they-work, maybe-they-kill-us harpoons?
对
Yeah.
这主意烂透了
It's a terrible idea.
你有更好的主意吗
You got a better one?
并没有
No. No.
-那么我们就算同意了 -对
- Then we're agreed. - Yeah.
-很好 -好极了
- Good. - Great.
蒙提斯
Montes!
该死
Shit.
我们走传统路线好了
Let's go old school.
市内电话也断线了
The landline's down, too.
好了 四周没人 我们上吧
Okay, coast is clear. Let's go.
它们竟然会走路
They can walk?
该死
Shit.
就是那些怪物
It's those things.
它们还没发现我们 好的
They haven't spotted us yet. Okay.
你还装了些什么
What else you got in here?
紧急应变用品
Emergency stuff.
好喔
Okay.
真的吗 保险套
Really? Condoms?
那是不同类型的紧急情况
Different kind of emergencies.
把那个递给我
Hand me that.
把嘴里的口香糖给我
Now hand me that gum in your mouth.
谢谢
Thank you.
只有一台水上摩托车
There's only one ski.
把你们的鱼叉给我
Give me your harpoons.
你确定
You sure?
-交给我吧 -祝你好运
- I got this. -  Good luck.
我们需要更强大的火力
We need more firepower.
对
Yeah.
我有个主意 我们走
I have an idea. Let's go.
这次不行 泰勒
Not this time, Taylor.
（欢乐岛）
应该就是这里
This should be the place.
来吧
Come on.
我们在找什么
What are we looking for?
硝酸铵
Ammonium nitrate.
你要制造炸弹
You're making a bomb?
这东西的威力和黄色炸药一样强大
This stuff is as powerful as TNT.
进去 进去
Get in! Get in!
不准动
Freeze!
来啊
Come on!
加油啊
来 去看看他有没有电话
Come on, let's see if he's got a phone.
我拿到卫星电话了 我拿到…
I got the sat phone. I got the sat...
我拿到电话了 你为何要偷他的钱
I got the phone. Why you stealing his money?
怎样 反正他又不需要
What? He's not gonna need it.
乖狗狗 乖狗狗
Nice doggies. Nice doggies.
好了 芮格斯
Okay, Rigas.
数到三 我们就狂奔
On the count of three, we're gonna bolt.
一 二 三
One. Two. Three!
搞什么 喂
What the hell? Hey!
等等DJ 等等DJ
Wait for DJ! Wait for DJ!
它们就在我们身后
They're right behind us!
我们躲进里面 快点 快进来
Let's hide in here! Come on. Come on. Come here. Come here.
-搞什么  -嗨 DJ 嗨 芮格斯
- What the hell? - Hi, DJ. Hi, Rigas.
所有人一起 靠在墙上 手举高
All of you together. Up against the wall. Hands up!
若我是你 就不会用那东西指着我
I wouldn't point that at me if I were you. Trust me.
闭嘴 双手举高
Shut it! Keep your hands in the air.
举手啊
Hands up!
我不想伤害你们
Don't want to hurt you,
所以我要给你们一次机会
so I'm going to give you one chance.
放下那些武器
Put those weapons down.
不然你会怎样
Or you'll do what?
别动 小矮子
Stay still, little guy.
不 乔 乔 小心门
No, no! Joe, Joe, door!
你们不准动
Stay where you are!
-快走 -找掩护
- Go, go! -  Get to cover!
可恶
Damn!
我有讯号了
I got signal.
打电话求助
Call for help!
然后前往海滩帮助别人
To get down to the beach and help people!
你要去哪
Where are you going?
-偷一架直升机 -什么直升机
- Stealing a chopper. -  What chopper?
全球救援
Global rescue?
我们需要救援 需要你派出所有手下
We need rescue! We need you to send everybody you got!
国民警卫队 救生员 海岸巡防队 任何人
The National Guard, the lifeguard, the Coast Guard. Anybody!
快来就对了
Just come now!
看起来其他人也有同样想法
Ugh, looks like someone else had the same idea.
我们需要一个计画
We need a plan.
我们必须把它引开 然后偷走直升机
We have to lead it away and steal the chopper.
好 你去引它 我去偷直升机
Okay, you lead it away, I'll steal the chopper.
-你来分散注意力 我去开直升机 -为什么是我
You distract it, I'll get the chopper. Why me?
你会驾驶直升机
Can you fly a chopper?
对 我会
Yeah, I can.
-你有驾照  -对 我有
- You have a license? - Yes, I do!
-真没想到 -什么
- I didn't know that. - What?
成交 好计画
Okay, good plan.
麦克
Mac!
九溟 我们得走了
Jiuming! We gotta go!
燃料 去拿燃料
Fuel! Get the fuel!
汽油 我们需要汽油
Gas! We need gas!
起飞
Get up!
把油枪拔掉
Get the fuel!
蜥蜴来袭 抓紧了
- Lizard incoming! Hold on!
九溟 九溟
Jiuming? Jiuming!
快跑
Run!
快走
Go!
好耶
Whoa, yay!
兄弟 没想到你能成功逃生
Man, I didn't think you were gonna make that one.
快逃
Run!
不
No.
你要去哪里 乔纳斯
Where are you going, Jonas?
飞低一点 那是玫盈
Get lower! That's Meiying!
你确定是玫盈
Are you sure it's Meiying?
再飞低一点
Get lower!
好啦 抓紧了
Okay, okay! Hold on!
玫盈
Meiying!
在这里
Over here!
跳起来
Leap up!
乔纳斯竟然还活着
Jonas is still alive?
载我过去
Get me over there!
救命啊
Help!
抓住 玫盈
Hang on, Meiying!
泰勒
Taylor!
出来啊
Come on!
快从桥下出来 小坏蛋
Come out from under the bridge, little troll!
游戏终于要结束了 对吧
End of the line, no?
我想是的
I guess it is.
你手上有枪
You got the gun.
我不会需要这个
I won't be needing this.
我就知道你下不了手
I knew you couldn't do it.
回头见 鱼饲料
See you later, chum.
舅
Jiu!
玫盈
Meiying!
把篓里的炸弹扔给我
Throw me the bomb!
在哪里
Where?
接着
Catch it!
坚持住 我来了
Hold on! I'm coming!
玫盈
Meiying!
乔纳斯 在这里
-  Jonas! Over here!
-你还好吗  -很好
- You okay? - Yeah.
九溟舅舅和麦克有麻烦了
Uncle Jiuming and Mac's in trouble.
待在这里 我马上回来
Stay here. I'll be right back.
麦克 你还好吗
Mac! Are you okay?
麦克
Mac?
来啊 你这个丑八怪
Come on, you ugly bastard!
快来 快来
Come on, come on, come on!
来 我接住你们了 来吧
Come on, come on. I got you, I got you. Come on, come on!
快点 小心 小心
Come on! Watch, watch, watch it!
来啊 来啊
Come on, come on, come on!
玫盈 你怎么在这里
Meiying, what are you doing here?
我必须救这只狗
I had to save the dog!
什么
What?
妈妈来了
Mommy's here.
-谢谢你 谢谢你 -不客气
- Thank you! Thank you! - You're welcome.
不行 你休想
Oh, no, you don't!
玫盈 过来
Meiying! Come!
就是这样 吃屎吧
Hell yeah! Get some!
是谁说点50口径不实用的
Who says a .50 caliber is an impractical round?
喂 等等 等等
Hey! Wait, wait, wait!
大家都保持静止 不要动
Everyone stay still. No motion.
不 没事的
No, it's okay.
那是海琪
That's Haiqi.
谁在乎是哪一只
Who cares which one it is?
它会听我的
She'll listen to me.
大家散开 这样就不会全被吃了
Let's spread out so that thing don't get us all.
我能搞定
I got this!
好耶 我就知道
Yes! I knew it!
我就跟你们说 我们心有灵犀
I told you! We have a special bond.
-它去追海豚了 -才怪
- It went after the dolphins. -  No!
它听从了我的指令
She obeyed my command.
真可笑
Ridiculous.
我以前就不信 现在更不信
I didn't believe it before and I don't believe it now.
喂 麦克 支援一下
Hey, Mac, back me up.
在它改变主意前我要先离开这里
I'm getting out of here before she changes her mind.
麦克
Mac!
你们继续留在这里争论
You guys stay there and argue.
它听从了我的指令
She obeyed my command!
-海豚 -才怪
- Dolphins. - No!
真的不是我的错
It's not my fault.
有时遇到突发状况 看到坏事发生
Sometimes, there's a situation, and bad things are happening,
你非得插手不可
and you just have to get involved.
很高兴你终于了解了
I'm glad you finally understand.
我以你为荣
I'm proud of you.
下次别再乱跑了 行吗
Next time don't run around, ok?
营救一号呼叫欢乐岛 结束
Rescue One to Fun Island. Over.
很高兴听到你的声音 老兄
Oh, it's good to hear your voice, man.
我们有很多需要帮助的人
We got a lot of people who need help.
对 我以前不会游泳 但后来…
Yeah, I used to didn't know how to swim, but then, you know,
要去外面追鲨鱼 就最好快点学会
you out there chasing sharks, you better learn how to swim quick!
水是冷 但也不是那么冷 但没错…
The water was cold. It wasn't that cold, but yeah,
-我其实玩得很开心 -海琪怎么办
- I was just having fun! -  What about Haiqi?
它还在外面 也许怀孕了
She's still out there. Maybe pregnant.
最好不要
Oh, preferably not.
那个明天再说
That's tomorrow.
今天 我们先珍惜现况
Today, we count our blessings.
这杯感谢我们还活着
Here's to being alive.
这杯敬海豚
Here's to dolphins.
敬老天保佑玫盈平安
To Meiying being safe.
更敬莎尔 兰斯 和寇蒂斯
And here's to Sal, Lance, and Curtis.
所以…
So...
我还会被禁足吗
am I still grounded?
-绝对会 -绝对会
- Absolutely. - Absolutely.
你们两个太可笑了
You two are ridiculous.
但无论如何我都爱你
But I love you anyway.
看来之前你有点鲁莽了
Looks like you got a little reckless out there.
不 一切完全在掌控之中
No, everything was totally under control.
最好是
Yeah, right.
可是现在一切都快要完全失控了
Well, everything's about to be totally not under control.
干杯
Give me some.
对 真是好酒
Yeah, that's the good stuff.
《巨齿鲨２：海沟深渊》
字幕翻译：张君怡